<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud on Sudeepthi Rebbalapalli</title><link>https://sudeepthi59o.github.io/categories/cloud/</link><description>Recent content in Cloud on Sudeepthi Rebbalapalli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sudeepthi59o.github.io/categories/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Predictive Maintenance Using AWS</title><link>https://sudeepthi59o.github.io/portfolio/predictive-maintainance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sudeepthi59o.github.io/portfolio/predictive-maintainance/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This project focuses on building a Predictive Maintenance system using the &lt;a href="https://archive.ics.uci.edu/dataset/682/ai4i+2020+predictive+maintenance+dataset">AI4I 2020 Predictive Maintenance Dataset&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/sagemaker/canvas/">AWS SageMaker Canvas&lt;/a>, a no-code ML platform. The goal is to predict machine failures before they occur based on operational and sensor data. By leveraging AWS services, the project efficiently processes and analyzes data to provide real-time predictions of equipment malfunctions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Key steps included data ingestion, cleaning, feature engineering, exploratory analysis, model building, evaluation, and basic explainability.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Global Development Index Analysis</title><link>https://sudeepthi59o.github.io/portfolio/human-development_index-gcp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sudeepthi59o.github.io/portfolio/human-development_index-gcp/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview">&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This project analyzes the evolution of global Human Development Index (HDI), Gender Development Index (GDI), and Gender Inequality Index (GII) from 1990 to 2023, using a cloud-based data pipeline and interactive visualizations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pipeline includes data collection, cleaning, storage in Google Cloud Platform (GCP) services, analysis using SQL queries in BigQuery, and visualization with Plotly. By integrating cloud-based processing and interactive charts, the project provides deeper insights into development patterns over time.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>